

Software Engineer, expanded experience .Net and Laravel Developer with +5 years of experience working in programming. Released 10+ projects for SQL database design and 9+ projects for web sites and web apps, and developed and maintained over 30 Laravel websites with 100% client satisfaction that resulted in \$1M revenue.

# **Education**

**University of Aleppo** 

Bachelor in Software Engineering

2012 - 2016

• GPA: 83.2%.

# Languages

- Arabic (native).
- English (fluent).

# **HASAN HAJJAR**

#### **FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

n Dubai - UAE

github.com/Eng-Hasan-Hajjar

eng.hasan.hajjar@gmail.com

+963 933 912 076

linkedin.com/in/hasan-hajjar-198429248/

### **WORK EXPERIENCES**

#### Web development manager

Mayar World-Remotely

2020-2022

- Architecting, designing, and building web app "PLS-services" to enable
  +1M visitors to have faster and best service for his house.
- Coordinating and training +7 software developers on the team and mentoring 5 members, grew office revenue by 200% in first nine months (representing 20% of company revenue).
- Troubleshooting and analyzing problems for about +20 web apps, thus business increased the company's revenue by 90%.
- Built the main website "Mayar World" using laravel framework that resulted in \$1.06M revenue, and +6 websites & web applications that brought in about \$1.05M within a 12-month period.
- Championed use of user feedback in program improvements, resulting in 50% boost in customer satisfaction ratings.
- Development tools: PHP, Laravel framework, Git, GitHub, Google Analytics, VS Code, JavaScript, SQL, Wrike project management and heroku.

#### Web developer

Alzahraa Company-Aleppo

2018-2020

- Evaluated new available +30 software technologies to help keep the services of the software department up-to-date, driving a 60% increase in new leads.
- Established "Aleppo Water", site with risk management and fraud detection techniques that facilitated +1M users to pay their receipts safely to Aleppo water institute.

## **Skills**

- Php/laravel, C#/Asp.net, HTML5,
  CSS3, jQuery, Bootstrap, MySQL,
  SQL Server, SQL Lite, Git, GitHub,
  API, REST API, WordPress, Java,
  C++, Python/Django, NodeJs, and
  Android.
- System Analyst, Data entry,
  Algorithms, Net Logo, OOP, Design patterns, Use case, Class,
   Sequence, and DFS diagrams.

# **Capabilities**

- Monitor applications and software systems 90%, planning projects in different environments including web and mobile 100%, and Ensure that applications are responsive 100%.
- Keeping abreast of developments in web applications and programming languages.
- Strong directing skills, ability to adapt and work with teamwork.
- Known for writing efficient, maintainable, and reusable code.
- Supervised the repository of code and documentation 95%.
- Wrote clean, clear, efficient, and maintainable code.

## **ACTIVITIES**

- Awarded the University's Al-Basel Award for Excellence in 2016.
- · Grades in mathematics 95%.

- Developed, automated and integrated +10 new modules and components in the .net C#/ASP web development environment, leading to a \$0.5M increase in new business for the company.
- Led full redesign of website with findings from customer segmentation and competitive research, increasing website leads by 200%.
- Acted as key contact for issue resolution and customer advocacy, reducing issues and complaints by over 45%.
- Development tools: Asp MVC .net, Visual Studio, C#, Telerik components, SQL server, MySQL, Oracle, MVP, MVVM, Jira, and VMware.

#### Web developer

#### Automata Group-Aleppo

2017-2018

- Expansion and preparation: computer software and hardware installation +75 operation, web design, +10 mobile applications
   Android and +2 e-commerce web development.
- Volunteered and tested sites in browsers and devices to ensure cross-browser compatibility and mobile responsiveness.
- Partnered and collaborated in analysis, design and requirements validation; increased average apps engagement time by 2x, 30% decrease in drop off rate, and 3x shares on social media.
- Launched to successfully complete more than 10 projects achieving an 80% reduction in the preparation time of them.
- Development tools: Visual Studio and Real time.

#### **Android developer**

freelance – Aleppo

2015-2017

- Built a notepad app called "your plans" using best practices methods in uploading photos with other services such as texts, allowed me to get a job later.
- Originated new architectures in Native Android using clean code techniques that were used in +10 projects which led to a 20% increase in productivity.